<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>Milletgrain</title>
        <link>https://lucaji.github.io/</link>
        <description>indie music artist and producer - software and hardware engineer</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><managingEditor>lucacipressi@gmail.com (Luca Cipressi)</managingEditor>
            <webMaster>lucacipressi@gmail.com (Luca Cipressi)</webMaster><copyright>This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial 4.0 International License.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Fri, 06 Jun 2025 00:00:00 &#43;0000</lastBuildDate>
            <atom:link href="https://lucaji.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
        <item>
    <title>🎵 Goats, Tea and Trouble — New Song Out Now 🌙</title>
    <link>https://lucaji.github.io/goats-tea-and-trouble/</link>
    <pubDate>Fri, 30 May 2025 00:00:00 &#43;0000</pubDate>
    <author>Luca Cipressi</author>
    <guid>https://lucaji.github.io/goats-tea-and-trouble/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<p>Some stories arrive long before the music does. Goats, Tea and Trouble began as a slow-burning tale told under starlight—a dreamlike fable set on Africa’s western coast, where ancient spells, unruly goats, and firelit music blur the line between myth and memory.</p>
<p>This song is the echo of that story: a soundscape born from a nomad’s bonfire, a missing cloth, and the quiet resistance of people who still live by rhythms older than time. Before you listen, read the story that inspired it.</p>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>La Magia e la Storia dei Luoghi siamo Noi</title>
    <link>https://lucaji.github.io/fotografia-storia-siamo-noi-live/</link>
    <pubDate>Sat, 25 Jan 2025 00:00:00 &#43;0000</pubDate>
    <author>Luca Cipressi</author>
    <guid>https://lucaji.github.io/fotografia-storia-siamo-noi-live/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<p>A live performance of theatre, music and dance along a photographic exhibit where sixteen photographers showcased their themed visual short-stories through their images, lead by the professional photographer <code>Pino Giannini</code>. Each tale begun with a narration by <code>Alessandra Arcieri</code>, with her voice setting the rightful mood, moments before a musical comment by Yours Truly started to engulf the theatre hall, with compelling beats and expressive textures paying hommage to the visual identity. The blindfolded dancer <code>Bruna Cerasa</code> coreographed with her harmonic movements and sudden twitches, thrills and body postures, the physical rendition of the stories.</p>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>🎵 Didjeing outta dog</title>
    <link>https://lucaji.github.io/didjeing-outta-dog-relaxing-australian-didgeridoo-yoga-beats/</link>
    <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jun 2024 00:00:00 &#43;0000</pubDate>
    <author>Luca Cipressi</author>
    <guid>https://lucaji.github.io/didjeing-outta-dog-relaxing-australian-didgeridoo-yoga-beats/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<p>It was one of those summer mornings when time feels almost paused — a tranquil pocket of stillness nestled within the city’s otherwise relentless pulse. The grass was already warm with sun, and the air carried the scent of cut leaves and waking soil. Beneath the shade of a tall plane tree, a small group had gathered on mats, in silent reverence to breath and body. At the center stood a yoga teacher, her posture fluid, calm, unhurried — an embodiment of presence.</p>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>Bass Guitar preamps comparison: Bartolini MK-1 vs. MarkBass MB-1</title>
    <link>https://lucaji.github.io/cort-bass-active-electronics/</link>
    <pubDate>Tue, 30 May 2023 13:44:23 &#43;0100</pubDate>
    <author>Luca Cipressi</author>
    <guid>https://lucaji.github.io/cort-bass-active-electronics/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[A side-by-side teardown and analysis of the Bartolini MK-1 and Markbass MB-1 preamps, highlighting key differences in circuit design, switch behavior, and signal handling.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>PikrellCam Motion-detection plus temperature Logger</title>
    <link>https://lucaji.github.io/pikrellcam-environmental-logger/</link>
    <pubDate>Sat, 29 Oct 2022 10:54:54 &#43;0600</pubDate>
    <author>Luca Cipressi</author>
    <guid>https://lucaji.github.io/pikrellcam-environmental-logger/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<h1 id="pikrellcam-reborn">PiKrellCam Reborn</h1>
<figure><a class="lightgallery" href="/pikrellcam-environmental-logger/pikrellcam-ui-01.jpg" title="/pikrellcam-environmental-logger/pikrellcam-ui-01.jpg" data-thumbnail="/pikrellcam-environmental-logger/pikrellcam-ui-01.jpg" data-sub-html="<h2>Logger UI panel.</h2>">
        
    </a><figcaption class="image-caption">Logger UI panel.</figcaption>
    </figure>
<h2 id="motion-detection-with-sensor-data-logger">Motion Detection with Sensor Data Logger</h2>
<blockquote>
<p>One of the most used motion detection and surveillance software for the Raspberry Pi with additional temperature and humidity logging and graph panel.</p></blockquote>
<figure><a class="lightgallery" href="/pikrellcam-environmental-logger/logger_screenshot_01.jpg" title="/pikrellcam-environmental-logger/logger_screenshot_01.jpg" data-thumbnail="/pikrellcam-environmental-logger/logger_screenshot_01.jpg" data-sub-html="<h2>Sensor Logger UI panel.</h2>">
        
    </a><figcaption class="image-caption">Sensor Logger UI panel.</figcaption>
    </figure>
<p>This fork introduces an additional web-dashboard driven by a <em>sqlite</em> database to keep track of temperature and humidity readings coming from a HDC1080 sensor. This dashboard is accessible by the main page of the camera preview bringing in some statistics of the collected data.</p>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>Data Logger for Electrical Power Measurements</title>
    <link>https://lucaji.github.io/electrical-power-measurements/</link>
    <pubDate>Tue, 19 Jan 2021 00:00:00 &#43;0000</pubDate>
    <author>Luca Cipressi</author>
    <guid>https://lucaji.github.io/electrical-power-measurements/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<h1 id="foreword">Foreword</h1>
<p>Measuring electrical power—whether consumed or supplied—over long durations can be essential for analyzing appliance behavior, validating designs, or performing reliability testing. Some measurement sessions may extend over hours or even days. In such scenarios, having a reliable software tool that can log data continuously, plot graphs, and export datasets becomes invaluable.</p>
<p>To support this need, I developed a utility named <strong>GPMLink</strong>, which interfaces with the <strong>GW-Instek GPM8310</strong> power meter. The software uses a Telnet-based interface to communicate with the device and periodically queries it using SCPI commands to retrieve integrated power metrics.</p>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>KAYABOARD - mag-lev organ keyboard (POC)</title>
    <link>https://lucaji.github.io/kayaboard/</link>
    <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jul 2020 11:04:49 &#43;0800</pubDate>
    <author>Luca Cipressi</author>
    <guid>https://lucaji.github.io/kayaboard/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<p>This is a Proof-Of-Concept of an <strong>organ keyboard</strong> using <strong>magnets</strong> instead of springs to obtain a nice upward release action and a decent downward counter-pressure when playing.</p>
<p>Designing a musical-instrument keyboard confronted me with some ergonomics considerations and material choices.
I did some research on magnets as well, to have a better understanding of their force irradiation and how to select them to save space, weight and achieve the best feeling when playing.</p>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>Restoration of an old open-air cinema PA</title>
    <link>https://lucaji.github.io/geloso-tube-amp-restoration/</link>
    <pubDate>Sun, 30 Oct 2016 00:00:00 &#43;0000</pubDate>
    <author>Luca Cipressi</author>
    <guid>https://lucaji.github.io/geloso-tube-amp-restoration/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<h1 id="geloso">GELOSO</h1>
<p>Geloso, founded in 1931 by Giovanni Geloso, was an Italian manufacturer of radios, televisions, amplifiers, amateur radio receivers, audio equipment and electronic components. Its headquarters were situated in Milan, Viale Brenta 29.</p>
<p>In 1931 the company started the production not only of radio sets but also most of the electronic components with which they were built and, over time, also developed and patented many others.</p>
<p>After the Second World War, Geloso expanded and expanded his production, becoming from 1950 onwards, a point of reference for enthusiasts of consumer electronics and hobbyists.</p>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>AM Radio on Arduino UNO</title>
    <link>https://lucaji.github.io/analog-radio/</link>
    <pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2015 00:00:00 &#43;0000</pubDate>
    <author>Luca Cipressi</author>
    <guid>https://lucaji.github.io/analog-radio/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<h2 id="-introduction">🛠️ Introduction</h2>
<p>This blog article gathers a series of <strong>DIY radio experiments</strong>, ranging from early analog detection with <em>Galena crystal receivers</em> to digitally driven AM transmission via <strong>Arduino microcontrollers</strong>. Inspired by a love for vintage radio sets and low-power communication techniques, this collection explores both the simplicity of early unpowered detection and the elegance of amplitude modulation (AM) implemented in modern embedded systems. These are primarily <strong>short-range (QRP)</strong> experiments — ideal for educational settings, hobbyists, and radio tinkerers looking to bridge past and present technologies.</p>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>DIY Tube Amps Builds 🎸</title>
    <link>https://lucaji.github.io/tube-amps/</link>
    <pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2015 00:00:00 &#43;0000</pubDate>
    <author>Luca Cipressi</author>
    <guid>https://lucaji.github.io/tube-amps/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<p>There are many many ways to build an amplifier, depending on money and time available, choosing the most expensive components, creating (or again, buy) a custom metal chassis (or have a friend that can make many as you want) with the objective to obtain a better build for the same price.</p>
<p>Building tube amps is very rewarding, and can keep you busy with its fair amount of metalwork and various power tools, like folding machines, press, lathe, milling machines and uncountable hand tools. Finishing the build with spray paint, adding lettering, logos, design elements one can go on forever. Custom shop!</p>]]></description>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
