<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>Electronics - Category - Milletgrain</title>
        <link>https://lucaji.github.io/categories/electronics/</link>
        <description>Electronics - Category - Milletgrain</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><managingEditor>lucacipressi@gmail.com (Luca Cipressi)</managingEditor>
            <webMaster>lucacipressi@gmail.com (Luca Cipressi)</webMaster><copyright>This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial 4.0 International License.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Tue, 30 May 2023 13:44:23 &#43;0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://lucaji.github.io/categories/electronics/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
    <title>Bass Guitar preamps comparison: Bartolini MK-1 vs. MarkBass MB-1</title>
    <link>https://lucaji.github.io/cort-bass-active-electronics/</link>
    <pubDate>Tue, 30 May 2023 13:44:23 &#43;0100</pubDate>
    <author>Luca Cipressi</author>
    <guid>https://lucaji.github.io/cort-bass-active-electronics/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[A side-by-side teardown and analysis of the Bartolini MK-1 and Markbass MB-1 preamps, highlighting key differences in circuit design, switch behavior, and signal handling.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>Data Logger for Electrical Power Measurements</title>
    <link>https://lucaji.github.io/electrical-power-measurements/</link>
    <pubDate>Tue, 19 Jan 2021 00:00:00 &#43;0000</pubDate>
    <author>Luca Cipressi</author>
    <guid>https://lucaji.github.io/electrical-power-measurements/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<h1 id="foreword">Foreword</h1>
<p>Measuring electrical power—whether consumed or supplied—over long durations can be essential for analyzing appliance behavior, validating designs, or performing reliability testing. Some measurement sessions may extend over hours or even days. In such scenarios, having a reliable software tool that can log data continuously, plot graphs, and export datasets becomes invaluable.</p>
<p>To support this need, I developed a utility named <strong>GPMLink</strong>, which interfaces with the <strong>GW-Instek GPM8310</strong> power meter. The software uses a Telnet-based interface to communicate with the device and periodically queries it using SCPI commands to retrieve integrated power metrics.</p>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>Restoration of an old open-air cinema PA</title>
    <link>https://lucaji.github.io/geloso-tube-amp-restoration/</link>
    <pubDate>Sun, 30 Oct 2016 00:00:00 &#43;0000</pubDate>
    <author>Luca Cipressi</author>
    <guid>https://lucaji.github.io/geloso-tube-amp-restoration/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<h1 id="geloso">GELOSO</h1>
<p>Geloso, founded in 1931 by Giovanni Geloso, was an Italian manufacturer of radios, televisions, amplifiers, amateur radio receivers, audio equipment and electronic components. Its headquarters were situated in Milan, Viale Brenta 29.</p>
<p>In 1931 the company started the production not only of radio sets but also most of the electronic components with which they were built and, over time, also developed and patented many others.</p>
<p>After the Second World War, Geloso expanded and expanded his production, becoming from 1950 onwards, a point of reference for enthusiasts of consumer electronics and hobbyists.</p>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>AM Radio on Arduino UNO</title>
    <link>https://lucaji.github.io/analog-radio/</link>
    <pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2015 00:00:00 &#43;0000</pubDate>
    <author>Luca Cipressi</author>
    <guid>https://lucaji.github.io/analog-radio/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<h2 id="-introduction">🛠️ Introduction</h2>
<p>This blog article gathers a series of <strong>DIY radio experiments</strong>, ranging from early analog detection with <em>Galena crystal receivers</em> to digitally driven AM transmission via <strong>Arduino microcontrollers</strong>. Inspired by a love for vintage radio sets and low-power communication techniques, this collection explores both the simplicity of early unpowered detection and the elegance of amplitude modulation (AM) implemented in modern embedded systems. These are primarily <strong>short-range (QRP)</strong> experiments — ideal for educational settings, hobbyists, and radio tinkerers looking to bridge past and present technologies.</p>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>DIY Tube Amps Builds 🎸</title>
    <link>https://lucaji.github.io/tube-amps/</link>
    <pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2015 00:00:00 &#43;0000</pubDate>
    <author>Luca Cipressi</author>
    <guid>https://lucaji.github.io/tube-amps/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<p>There are many many ways to build an amplifier, depending on money and time available, choosing the most expensive components, creating (or again, buy) a custom metal chassis (or have a friend that can make many as you want) with the objective to obtain a better build for the same price.</p>
<p>Building tube amps is very rewarding, and can keep you busy with its fair amount of metalwork and various power tools, like folding machines, press, lathe, milling machines and uncountable hand tools. Finishing the build with spray paint, adding lettering, logos, design elements one can go on forever. Custom shop!</p>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>Diretta Iniezione</title>
    <link>https://lucaji.github.io/di-box/</link>
    <pubDate>Sat, 20 Sep 2014 00:00:00 &#43;0000</pubDate>
    <author>Luca Cipressi</author>
    <guid>https://lucaji.github.io/di-box/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<h1 id="di-box">DI Box</h1>
<p>A handcrafted <strong>direct injection box</strong> — a compact, AC-powered <strong>audio preamplifier</strong> designed for dynamic microphones, capable of cleanly converting mic-level signals to standard <strong>line-level output (-10dBV)</strong>.</p>
<h3 id="features">Features:</h3>
<ul>
<li>Class A <strong>FET input stage</strong> with high linearity and extended bandwidth</li>
<li>XLR input with adjustable gain</li>
<li>Balanced or unbalanced <strong>line-level output</strong></li>
<li>Low noise, low distortion performance</li>
<li>Wide frequency response</li>
</ul>
<hr>
<h2 id="-motivation--design-approach">🎙️ Motivation &amp; Design Approach</h2>
<p>While trying to record audio using a <strong>Shure SM58</strong> dynamic microphone directly into a Mac’s line-in jack, I encountered the usual issues: low gain, poor signal-to-noise ratio, and uninspiring tone. So, I decided to build my own solution — a clean, simple <strong>preamplifier</strong> with tone characteristics I personally enjoy.</p>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>DeLorean Time Circuits</title>
    <link>https://lucaji.github.io/back-to-the-future-clock-replica/</link>
    <pubDate>Mon, 07 Apr 2014 00:00:00 &#43;0000</pubDate>
    <author>Luca Cipressi</author>
    <guid>https://lucaji.github.io/back-to-the-future-clock-replica/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<h1 id="back-to-the-future">Back To The Future</h1>
<p>This is a semi-serious rendition of the story behind the making of this project —<br>
a <strong>replica of the Time Circuits from <em>Back to the Future</em></strong>, turned into a <strong>talking alarm clock</strong>.</p>
<p>Aside from actual time travel (which may or may not be possible depending on your time zone, ISP, and your ability to construct a <a href="https://backtothefuture.fandom.com/wiki/Flux_capacitor" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer ">flux capacitor</a>), it works beautifully as a nostalgic gadget, delivering iconic quotes from the film.</p>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>Theremin</title>
    <link>https://lucaji.github.io/theremin/</link>
    <pubDate>Sun, 13 Oct 2013 00:00:00 &#43;0000</pubDate>
    <author>Luca Cipressi</author>
    <guid>https://lucaji.github.io/theremin/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<p>A mighty Theremin build from an open source project powered by an Arduino UNO.</p>]]></description>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
