<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>Roli - Tag - Milletgrain</title>
        <link>https://lucaji.github.io/tags/roli/</link>
        <description>Roli - Tag - Milletgrain</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><managingEditor>lucacipressi@gmail.com (Luca Cipressi)</managingEditor>
            <webMaster>lucacipressi@gmail.com (Luca Cipressi)</webMaster><copyright>This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial 4.0 International License.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sat, 25 Jan 2025 00:00:00 &#43;0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://lucaji.github.io/tags/roli/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
    <title>La Magia e la Storia dei Luoghi siamo Noi</title>
    <link>https://lucaji.github.io/fotografia-storia-siamo-noi-live/</link>
    <pubDate>Sat, 25 Jan 2025 00:00:00 &#43;0000</pubDate>
    <author>Luca Cipressi</author>
    <guid>https://lucaji.github.io/fotografia-storia-siamo-noi-live/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<p>A live performance of theatre, music and dance along a photographic exhibit where sixteen photographers showcased their themed visual short-stories through their images, lead by the professional photographer <code>Pino Giannini</code>. Each tale begun with a narration by <code>Alessandra Arcieri</code>, with her voice setting the rightful mood, moments before a musical comment by Yours Truly started to engulf the theatre hall, with compelling beats and expressive textures paying hommage to the visual identity. The blindfolded dancer <code>Bruna Cerasa</code> coreographed with her harmonic movements and sudden twitches, thrills and body postures, the physical rendition of the stories.</p>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>🎵 Didjeing outta dog</title>
    <link>https://lucaji.github.io/didjeing-outta-dog-relaxing-australian-didgeridoo-yoga-beats/</link>
    <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jun 2024 00:00:00 &#43;0000</pubDate>
    <author>Luca Cipressi</author>
    <guid>https://lucaji.github.io/didjeing-outta-dog-relaxing-australian-didgeridoo-yoga-beats/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<p>It was one of those summer mornings when time feels almost paused — a tranquil pocket of stillness nestled within the city’s otherwise relentless pulse. The grass was already warm with sun, and the air carried the scent of cut leaves and waking soil. Beneath the shade of a tall plane tree, a small group had gathered on mats, in silent reverence to breath and body. At the center stood a yoga teacher, her posture fluid, calm, unhurried — an embodiment of presence.</p>]]></description>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
