<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>Music - Tag - Milletgrain</title>
        <link>https://lucaji.github.io/tags/music/</link>
        <description>Music - Tag - Milletgrain</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><managingEditor>lucacipressi@gmail.com (Luca Cipressi)</managingEditor>
            <webMaster>lucacipressi@gmail.com (Luca Cipressi)</webMaster><copyright>This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial 4.0 International License.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Fri, 30 May 2025 00:00:00 &#43;0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://lucaji.github.io/tags/music/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
    <title>🎵 Goats, Tea and Trouble — New Song Out Now 🌙</title>
    <link>https://lucaji.github.io/goats-tea-and-trouble/</link>
    <pubDate>Fri, 30 May 2025 00:00:00 &#43;0000</pubDate>
    <author>Luca Cipressi</author>
    <guid>https://lucaji.github.io/goats-tea-and-trouble/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<p>Some stories arrive long before the music does. Goats, Tea and Trouble began as a slow-burning tale told under starlight—a dreamlike fable set on Africa’s western coast, where ancient spells, unruly goats, and firelit music blur the line between myth and memory.</p>
<p>This song is the echo of that story: a soundscape born from a nomad’s bonfire, a missing cloth, and the quiet resistance of people who still live by rhythms older than time. Before you listen, read the story that inspired it.</p>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>🎵 Didjeing outta dog</title>
    <link>https://lucaji.github.io/didjeing-outta-dog-relaxing-australian-didgeridoo-yoga-beats/</link>
    <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jun 2024 00:00:00 &#43;0000</pubDate>
    <author>Luca Cipressi</author>
    <guid>https://lucaji.github.io/didjeing-outta-dog-relaxing-australian-didgeridoo-yoga-beats/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<p>It was one of those summer mornings when time feels almost paused — a tranquil pocket of stillness nestled within the city’s otherwise relentless pulse. The grass was already warm with sun, and the air carried the scent of cut leaves and waking soil. Beneath the shade of a tall plane tree, a small group had gathered on mats, in silent reverence to breath and body. At the center stood a yoga teacher, her posture fluid, calm, unhurried — an embodiment of presence.</p>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>KAYABOARD - mag-lev organ keyboard (POC)</title>
    <link>https://lucaji.github.io/kayaboard/</link>
    <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jul 2020 11:04:49 &#43;0800</pubDate>
    <author>Luca Cipressi</author>
    <guid>https://lucaji.github.io/kayaboard/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<p>This is a Proof-Of-Concept of an <strong>organ keyboard</strong> using <strong>magnets</strong> instead of springs to obtain a nice upward release action and a decent downward counter-pressure when playing.</p>
<p>Designing a musical-instrument keyboard confronted me with some ergonomics considerations and material choices.
I did some research on magnets as well, to have a better understanding of their force irradiation and how to select them to save space, weight and achieve the best feeling when playing.</p>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>Campari Dreaming - Honey Ants Jam Session Night</title>
    <link>https://lucaji.github.io/honey-ants-dreaming-jam-session/</link>
    <pubDate>Tue, 15 Jul 2014 16:54:54 &#43;0600</pubDate>
    <author>Luca Cipressi</author>
    <guid>https://lucaji.github.io/honey-ants-dreaming-jam-session/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<h2 id="crafting-the-leaflet-a-night-at-bar-dello-sport">Crafting the Leaflet: A Night at Bar dello Sport</h2>
<p>It all began with a casual evening at <strong>Bar dello Sport</strong> in Serramonacesca, sipping on the iconic Italian drink—<a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Campari" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer ">Campari Soda</a>—amid the warm embrace of local hospitality. Conversations drifted freely among friends and locals, and an idea sparked: designing a unique promotional poster for an upcoming jam session night sponsored by Campari. Fueled by inspiration (and a few rounds of drinks), I eagerly offered my skills as a graphic designer to craft the flyer.</p>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>Lorena Fontana - A Vision - Making of</title>
    <link>https://lucaji.github.io/lorena-fontana-a-vision/</link>
    <pubDate>Sun, 15 Sep 2013 16:54:54 &#43;0600</pubDate>
    <author>Luca Cipressi</author>
    <guid>https://lucaji.github.io/lorena-fontana-a-vision/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<p>This video is the official behind-the-scenes documentary filmed in Los Angeles during the recording sessions of <strong>A Vision</strong>, an original jazz album by Italian vocalist, educator, and composer <a href="https://it.wikipedia.org/wiki/Lorena_Fontana" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer ">Lorena Fontana</a>. I had the opportunity to fully edit and assemble the video, and the result reflects the intimate, professional, and collaborative atmosphere that only top-tier musicians in LA can create.</p>
<h2 id="the-project">The Project</h2>
<p>Recorded at the renowned studio of <strong>Dennis Moody</strong>, the production captures the magic of live jazz performance while blending modern vocal arrangements with traditional acoustic instrumentation.</p>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>Fire Makers - Metal Empire</title>
    <link>https://lucaji.github.io/firemakers-metal-empire/</link>
    <pubDate>Fri, 23 Nov 2007 09:17:17 -0800</pubDate>
    <author>Luca Cipressi</author>
    <guid>https://lucaji.github.io/firemakers-metal-empire/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<h1 id="fire-makers--metal-empire">Fire Makers – Metal Empire</h1>
<p>In 2005, during a gap between travels and projects, I had the chance to collaborate as a guest keyboardist for an independent metal band named <a href="https://www.facebook.com/firemakersmetalband" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer ">Fire Makers</a>. They were in the process of recording their debut album <em>Metal Empire</em>, and I was invited to contribute organ, piano, and synthesizer parts on several tracks.</p>
<p>It turned out to be an electrifying and high-adrenaline experience. What struck me most was the stunning voice of their lead vocalist at the time—none other than <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Eugent_Bushpepa" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer ">Eugent Bushpepa</a>, who would later rise to prominence on international stages.</p>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>The Leslie Speaker</title>
    <link>https://lucaji.github.io/leslie-speaker/</link>
    <pubDate>Sun, 02 Jul 2006 11:04:49 &#43;0800</pubDate>
    <author>Luca Cipressi</author>
    <guid>https://lucaji.github.io/leslie-speaker/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<blockquote>
<p>This article explains the principles behind Leslie-type loudspeakers and goes on to describe the construction of a generously proportioned system intended for use with a home constructed electronic organ. The article could provide the starting point from which individual readers could build up a rotating loudspeaker system to suit their own particular requirements.</p></blockquote>
<h1 id="rotating-system-loudspeakers-for-electronic-organs">Rotating System Loudspeakers for Electronic Organs</h1>
<p>The most obvious and the routine method of radiating sound from an electronic organ is by means of one or more loudspeakers, suitably and conventionally baffled. In a single-unit instrument, the loudspeaker(s) are mounted behind cutouts, usually in the front panel below the keyboard and above the pedal clavier.
While compact and convenient, this arrangement usually suffers some limitation in the effectiveness of the baffling which can be provided and the efficiency with which the sound can be propagated.</p>]]></description>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
