<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>Media - Category - Lucaji</title>
        <link>https://lucaji.github.io/categories/media/</link>
        <description>Media - Category - Lucaji</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><managingEditor>lucaji()mail(.)ru (Luca Cipressi)</managingEditor>
            <webMaster>lucaji()mail(.)ru (Luca Cipressi)</webMaster><copyright>This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial 4.0 International License.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2015 00:00:00 &#43;0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://lucaji.github.io/categories/media/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
    <title>Proiezione Origami - Book Cover Design</title>
    <link>https://lucaji.github.io/proiezione-origami/</link>
    <pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2015 00:00:00 &#43;0000</pubDate>
    <author>Luca Cipressi</author>
    <guid>https://lucaji.github.io/proiezione-origami/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<p>I designed the cover for this enthralling <strong>cyberzen</strong> story, rich in obfuscated structures that only electricity can uncover.</p>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>Campari Dreaming - Honey Ants Jam Session Night</title>
    <link>https://lucaji.github.io/campari-honey-ants/</link>
    <pubDate>Tue, 15 Jul 2014 16:54:54 &#43;0600</pubDate>
    <author>Luca Cipressi</author>
    <guid>https://lucaji.github.io/campari-honey-ants/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[I designed these leaflets for a jam session night at Bar dello Sport, Serramonacesca using the images of Tjalas, the aboriginal name for this specimen of honey pot ants in central Australia, with their abdomen swollen with the sweetest honey you could ever think of.
We were staying in Serramonacesca, me and my old lady. Used often to spend there some holidays together. I got this invitation to a jam session night while drinking at the very place with the locals.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>Lorena Fontana - A Vision - Making of</title>
    <link>https://lucaji.github.io/lorena-fontana-a-vision/</link>
    <pubDate>Sun, 15 Sep 2013 16:54:54 &#43;0600</pubDate>
    <author>Luca Cipressi</author>
    <guid>https://lucaji.github.io/lorena-fontana-a-vision/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<p>This video is the official behind-the-scenes in LA while recording <strong>A Vision</strong> by Lorena Fontana, in the studios of Dennis Moody. I had the fortune to fully edit and assemble the video footage which gives a nice rendition of the atmosphere only professional musicians can breathe.</p>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>Fire Makers - Metal Empire</title>
    <link>https://lucaji.github.io/firemakers/</link>
    <pubDate>Fri, 23 Nov 2007 09:17:17 -0800</pubDate>
    <author>Luca Cipressi</author>
    <guid>https://lucaji.github.io/firemakers/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[In between my travels I participated as guest keyboard player for a metal-band project while they were recording and releasing their album &ldquo;Metal Empire&rdquo;, the band name was Fire Makers.
I was very impressed by the lead singer, as it turned out he was Eugent Bushpepa.
For this recording I played the organ parts on a Roland VK-8 and the piano/synths part on a GEM S3.
I sincerely wish to thank Max &ldquo;Dingo&rdquo; Candido for that brief but intense experience.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>Visual Communication and Video Acquisition</title>
    <link>https://lucaji.github.io/video-acquisition/</link>
    <pubDate>Sat, 10 Jun 2000 00:00:00 &#43;0000</pubDate>
    <author>Luca Cipressi</author>
    <guid>https://lucaji.github.io/video-acquisition/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[Foreword This is a transcription of my Diploma thesis simply titled &ldquo;Visual Communication&rdquo; written in June 2000.
The topic is woven around Visual Communication, an emerging trend in computer science in those years. Personal computers were just beginning to gain more computing power, little by little, slowly approaching that of mainframes of the era. Digital Signal Processing was out-of-the-question for a little home computer. But the direction was set, and soon enough, some decades later we can do the unthinkable on our notebooks now.]]></description>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
