<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>Media - Category - Milletgrain</title>
        <link>https://lucaji.github.io/categories/media/</link>
        <description>Media - Category - Milletgrain</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><managingEditor>lucacipressi()gmail(.)com (Luca Cipressi)</managingEditor>
            <webMaster>lucacipressi()gmail(.)com (Luca Cipressi)</webMaster><copyright>This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial 4.0 International License.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2015 00:00:00 &#43;0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://lucaji.github.io/categories/media/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
    <title>Proiezione Origami - Book Cover Design</title>
    <link>https://lucaji.github.io/proiezione-origami-book-cover-design/</link>
    <pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2015 00:00:00 &#43;0000</pubDate>
    <author>Luca Cipressi</author>
    <guid>https://lucaji.github.io/proiezione-origami-book-cover-design/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<p>I designed the cover for this enthralling <strong>cyberzen</strong> story, rich in obfuscated structures that only electricity can uncover.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Rome, New York, Bombay. What will be the next target? In a scenario รก-la Blade Runner, in a time marked by attacks and dominated by the logics of psycho-empowering games, every experience is transformed into Agone and every gamer in Ludopath. The jingle of the new role-playing game is a song by the TV musical &ldquo;Fame&rdquo;, inspired by the verses of Walt Whitman. Among these verses lies the secret of Agent Alpha&rsquo;s mission. The rebel player, determined to neutralize the mother-company and to discover the identity of the powerful demiurge, will have to deal with a fearsome opponent sent to flush her out, some mercenaries and a series of events created on-spot by the game. Among excellent university campuses, historic cities and metropolis with gray tones, all is played without the exclusion of blows. Alpha has a precious ally, a valid Master and a secret and very powerful energy resource, which she does not yet know. She will first have to sing the electric body. Finalist book at BUK Modena 2017.</p>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>Campari Dreaming - Honey Ants Jam Session Night</title>
    <link>https://lucaji.github.io/honey-ants-dreaming-jam-session/</link>
    <pubDate>Tue, 15 Jul 2014 16:54:54 &#43;0600</pubDate>
    <author>Luca Cipressi</author>
    <guid>https://lucaji.github.io/honey-ants-dreaming-jam-session/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<p>I designed these leaflets for a jam session night at <strong>Bar dello Sport, Serramonacesca</strong> using the images of <em>Tjalas</em>, the aboriginal name for this specimen of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Honeypot_ant" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer ">honey pot ants</a> in central Australia, with their abdomen swollen with the sweetest <strong>honey</strong> you could ever think of.</p>
<p>We were staying in Serramonacesca, me and my old lady. Used often to spend there some holidays together. I got this invitation to a jam session night while drinking at the very place with the locals. I offered to draw the leaflet, got the ok, had more rounds till I went back home late that night to work on the poster.</p>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>Lorena Fontana - A Vision - Making of</title>
    <link>https://lucaji.github.io/lorena-fontana-a-vision/</link>
    <pubDate>Sun, 15 Sep 2013 16:54:54 &#43;0600</pubDate>
    <author>Luca Cipressi</author>
    <guid>https://lucaji.github.io/lorena-fontana-a-vision/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<p>This video is the official behind-the-scenes in LA while recording <strong>A Vision</strong> by Lorena Fontana, in the studios of Dennis Moody. I had the fortune to fully edit and assemble the video footage which gives a nice rendition of the atmosphere only professional musicians can breathe.</p>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>Fire Makers - Metal Empire</title>
    <link>https://lucaji.github.io/firemakers-metal-empire/</link>
    <pubDate>Fri, 23 Nov 2007 09:17:17 -0800</pubDate>
    <author>Luca Cipressi</author>
    <guid>https://lucaji.github.io/firemakers-metal-empire/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<p>In between my travels I participated as guest keyboard player for a metal-band project while they were recording and releasing their album &ldquo;Metal Empire&rdquo;, the band name was <a href="https://www.facebook.com/firemakersmetalband" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer ">Fire Makers</a>.</p>
<p>I was very impressed by the lead singer, as it turned out he was <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Eugent_Bushpepa" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer ">Eugent Bushpepa</a>.</p>
<div style="position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;">
      <iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share; fullscreen" loading="eager" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/WdRE4tFt2H4?autoplay=0&amp;controls=1&amp;end=0&amp;loop=0&amp;mute=0&amp;start=0" style="position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;" title="YouTube video"></iframe>
    </div>

<p>For this recording I played the organ parts on a Roland VK-8 and the piano/synths part on a GEM S3.</p>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>Visual Communication and Video Acquisition</title>
    <link>https://lucaji.github.io/diploma/</link>
    <pubDate>Sat, 10 Jun 2000 00:00:00 &#43;0000</pubDate>
    <author>Luca Cipressi</author>
    <guid>https://lucaji.github.io/diploma/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<h1 id="foreword">Foreword</h1>
<p>This is a transcription of my Diploma thesis simply titled &ldquo;<strong>Visual Communication</strong>&rdquo; written in June 2000.</p>
<p>The topic is woven around Visual Communication, an emerging trend in computer science in those years.
Personal computers were just beginning to gain more computing power, little by little, slowly approaching that of mainframes of the era. Digital Signal Processing was out-of-the-question for a little home computer.
But the direction was set, and soon enough, some decades later we can do the unthinkable on our notebooks now.</p>]]></description>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
