<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>Tube Amps - Tag - Lucaji</title>
        <link>https://lucaji.github.io/tags/tube-amps/</link>
        <description>Tube Amps - Tag - Lucaji</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><managingEditor>lucaji()mail(.)ru (Luca Cipressi)</managingEditor>
            <webMaster>lucaji()mail(.)ru (Luca Cipressi)</webMaster><copyright>This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial 4.0 International License.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sun, 30 Oct 2016 00:00:00 &#43;0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://lucaji.github.io/tags/tube-amps/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
    <title>Restoration of an old open-air cinema PA</title>
    <link>https://lucaji.github.io/geloso-tube-amp-restoration/</link>
    <pubDate>Sun, 30 Oct 2016 00:00:00 &#43;0000</pubDate>
    <author>Luca Cipressi</author>
    <guid>https://lucaji.github.io/geloso-tube-amp-restoration/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[GELOSO Geloso, founded in 1931 by Giovanni Geloso, was an Italian manufacturer of radios, televisions, amplifiers, amateur radio receivers, audio equipment and electronic components. Its headquarters were situated in Milan, Viale Brenta 29.
In 1931 the company started the production not only of radio sets but also most of the electronic components with which they were built and, over time, also developed and patented many others.
After the Second World War, Geloso expanded and expanded his production, becoming from 1950 onwards, a point of reference for enthusiasts of consumer electronics and hobbyists.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>Tube Amps Builds 🎸</title>
    <link>https://lucaji.github.io/tube-amps/</link>
    <pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2015 00:00:00 &#43;0000</pubDate>
    <author>Luca Cipressi</author>
    <guid>https://lucaji.github.io/tube-amps/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[Building Tube Amps Builds builds your knowledge and skills There are many many ways to build an amplifier, depending on money and time available, choosing the most expensive components, creating (or again, buy) a custom metal chassis (or have a friend that can make many as you want) with the objective to obtain a better build for the same price.
Building tube amps is very rewarding, and can keep you busy with its fair amount of metalwork and various power tools, like folding machines, press, lathe, milling machines and uncountable hand tools.]]></description>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
