<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>SONGS - Category - Milletgrain</title>
        <link>https://lucaji.github.io/categories/songs/</link>
        <description>SONGS - Category - Milletgrain</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><managingEditor>lucacipressi@gmail.com (Luca Cipressi)</managingEditor>
            <webMaster>lucacipressi@gmail.com (Luca Cipressi)</webMaster><copyright>This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial 4.0 International License.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Fri, 30 May 2025 00:00:00 &#43;0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://lucaji.github.io/categories/songs/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
    <title>🎵 Goats, Tea and Trouble — New Song Out Now 🌙</title>
    <link>https://lucaji.github.io/goats-tea-and-trouble/</link>
    <pubDate>Fri, 30 May 2025 00:00:00 &#43;0000</pubDate>
    <author>Luca Cipressi</author>
    <guid>https://lucaji.github.io/goats-tea-and-trouble/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<p>Some stories arrive long before the music does. Goats, Tea and Trouble began as a slow-burning tale told under starlight—a dreamlike fable set on Africa’s western coast, where ancient spells, unruly goats, and firelit music blur the line between myth and memory.</p>
<p>This song is the echo of that story: a soundscape born from a nomad’s bonfire, a missing cloth, and the quiet resistance of people who still live by rhythms older than time. Before you listen, read the story that inspired it.</p>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>🎵 Didjeing outta dog</title>
    <link>https://lucaji.github.io/didjeing-outta-dog-relaxing-australian-didgeridoo-yoga-beats/</link>
    <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jun 2024 00:00:00 &#43;0000</pubDate>
    <author>Luca Cipressi</author>
    <guid>https://lucaji.github.io/didjeing-outta-dog-relaxing-australian-didgeridoo-yoga-beats/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<p>It was one of those summer mornings when time feels almost paused — a tranquil pocket of stillness nestled within the city’s otherwise relentless pulse. The grass was already warm with sun, and the air carried the scent of cut leaves and waking soil. Beneath the shade of a tall plane tree, a small group had gathered on mats, in silent reverence to breath and body. At the center stood a yoga teacher, her posture fluid, calm, unhurried — an embodiment of presence.</p>]]></description>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
